<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on ELL Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/life/</link>
    <description>ELL Blog (Life)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 19:12:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Cite Your Factual Opinions - The Illusion of Truth</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/please-cite-your-factual-opinions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 19:12:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/please-cite-your-factual-opinions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently thought about why birth rates in all developed countries except for Israel are declining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;My intuition tells me it has to do with culture. Click for more thoughts&lt;/summary&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe this because in Israel there is a strong culture of having children, going as far as to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2023-11-09/ty-article-magazine/.premium/we-operate-24-7-the-race-to-preserve-israeli-soldiers-sperm/0000018b-af34-dea2-a9bf-ffbee1470000&#34;&gt;extract semen from dead soldiers&lt;/a&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s not discuss the morals of this as it&amp;rsquo;s clear in every society that exceptions are made for rules that would be considered wrong in other situations. Examples: for COVID-19 vaccines, the health of the population is more important than bodily rights; In several US states, the right to be born is more important than the right of both bodily autonomy and even property rights (i.e. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/abortion-simplified&#34;&gt;the right to remove a trespasser even if the trespasser is deceased&lt;/a&gt;); In the Israeli case, population growth is more important than bodily autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaaanyways, I came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/sociology/comments/1anl3py/comment/kpts26j/&#34;&gt;Reddit comment&lt;/a&gt; (I know I know, I also loathe Reddit), and there are ZERO citations in this top comment regarding the eight claims it made. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at these claims. Almost all of these are accepted based on Redditor biases and not hard evidence based research. How else do people end up believing that bike lanes cause congestion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not a discussion on intelligence or being more analytical than the average person, there is a lack of culture to &lt;strong&gt;SEEK THE TRUTH&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;ILLUSION OF TRUTH&lt;/strong&gt; exists, and it&amp;rsquo;s clearly very prevalent among liberals. Before I begin I&amp;rsquo;d like to share quote because it needs to be made into a shirt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a huge literature on fertility decline with development in demography, much of it written by sociologists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that so? Let me apply the Socratic method. How do you know? Let&amp;rsquo;s search for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/action/doSearch?field1=Title&amp;amp;text1=declining+birth+rates&amp;amp;publication=&amp;amp;Ppub=&#34;&gt;onlinelibrary.wiley.com: title search for declining birth rates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the bigger theme is not just about understanding why birth rates are declining, but what we can do about it, let&amp;rsquo;s look at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1728-4457.2012.00506.x&#34;&gt;Noriyuki Takayama and Martin Werding (eds.), Fertility and Public Policy: How to Reverse the Trend of Declining Birth Rates&lt;/a&gt; which was published on 27 June 2012. So 12 years have gone by, and birth rates have not shot up. 50 US dollars to read the PDF? Why not? I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to my reading list. I&amp;rsquo;ll update this article and post a new one once I do. Assuming this article is correct, are all developed country policy makers just incompetent? Is that a valid answer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Women face higher opportunity costs to childbearing in today&amp;rsquo;s society than previous society&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure there is a cost to bear a child, however would an adopter not agree that the consumer surplus of paying to adopt a child is infinite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile work institutions that were established on the assumption of a breadwinner / homemaker model have adapted incompletely to the two-earner household, and work/life balance/integration issues have accordingly intensified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? This makes no sense. If anything, workplaces have NOT adapted to the two-earner household. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsweek.com/russians-told-make-babies-work-breaks-1954429&#34;&gt;Russia understands this&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m trying my best not to add non-cited opinions, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it at that. Basically, 7 hour shifts, 5 days a week is normalized in all developed cultures, and there are only a very few cases where work hours can go down while leisure goes up. Where are the part-time white collar workers and jobs? Please call me (as in I&amp;rsquo;m curious what you do). The only thing I can really think of is if workplace institutions started rewarding the most productive employees by reducing work hours and pushing workers to get married and have children. In developed country, this would be illegal due to discrimination, but at least in Canada we have section 33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with these economic and institutional changes have come cultural changes such that marriage is viewed as a capstone at the end of young adulthood rather than its foundation at the beginning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What? Millennials making things up. What&amp;rsquo;s next, thinking Gen X isn&amp;rsquo;t liberal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;marriage and childbearing have become decoupled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No elaboration on how birth rates decline due to decoupling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;decisions are more individualized and less subject to family and cultural pressures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time humans died very young and humans did not need family and cultural pressures to grow a population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with advancing globalization our economic fortunes have come to seem much more uncertain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument these people seem to make is that you need to afford a house to have children, but do not consider that maybe housing prices have also adjusted to two-earner couples? Sure I need to confirm based on housing prices to household incomes, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any studies that look at only millennials. The oldest millennials started working in the early 2000s, and did not lose money in the dotcom bubble, real wages continued growing past 2010, and had the opportunity to ride one of the longest bull market in history, while technology got much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;kind of cultural pessimism has taken hold perhaps in tandem, making the decision to bring a child into the world seem riskier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again? Is there a word for having mentally illness due to being chronically online?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Not to Negotiate a Job Offer</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/how-not-to-negotiate-a-job-offer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 19:24:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/how-not-to-negotiate-a-job-offer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some people, a job offer is a massive ego boost. I&amp;rsquo;ll be truthful - my ego is substantial, perhaps immeasurable, but I never let it cloud my judgment (not my ego speaking I swear). Once a person reaches mental maturity, they should be able to silence those nagging whispers from their ego. An unchecked ego unnecessarily muddies decision-making and can lead to devastating consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This recant is of someone who we&amp;rsquo;ll call Vic, who was being mentored by a friend of mine, Rachel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel excels at guiding candidates at interviews for product manager roles. I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about the stereotypical product manager who lacks the underlying technical knowledge - I&amp;rsquo;m talking about specialists in their respective technical fields. In other words workers who deserve to climb the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex received a job offer from a Fortune 500 company that would quadruple their current compensation, with the stipulation being that the role got converted to 100% onsite in a high cost of living area compared to his current hybrid role (both in the US). Alex&amp;rsquo;s response? Asking for more compensation because of relocation but also for a two month deferral! Due to the &amp;ldquo;holidays.&amp;rdquo; Why would you apply to a role if you aren&amp;rsquo;t even going to want to start for 2 months? Why would you willingly get paid 4x less for 2 months???  You could fly back home every weekend with a stopover in Las Vegas, gamble away $1,000 nightly at the casino, and still come out ahead financially! Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s precisely what you should do - for two months, gamble away the net pay after subtracting the cost of travel and rent. Even if gambling is self-harm, a shift in perspective is all that&amp;rsquo;s required to not feel those losses emotionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justifiably, this Fortune 500 company did not tolerate any of this bullshit and told him they went with another candidate. They told him that it seems he really cared about the holidays. From my perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s plain disrespectful to tell someone that you can&amp;rsquo;t start asap because you want to stay a few months before the holidays?? Not to mention that if the compensation is that high, it signals that the role is crucial to the organization (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.snagajob.com/jobs/870614703&#34;&gt;not MGM hahhaha&lt;/a&gt;), they really can&amp;rsquo;t be entertaining time wasters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
