<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on ELL Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/ethics/</link>
    <description>ELL Blog (Ethics)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 22:54:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Audible Is Unethical</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/amazon-audible-is-unethical/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 22:54:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/amazon-audible-is-unethical/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I realized I was being charged US$15/month for a whole year by Amazon Audible. The reason? A free trial cancellation that did not go through fully.
You see, to cancel amazon audible, you need to go to your account, then the membership, then click cancel. Then you have to give a reason for cancelling.
Then you are taken to a page that simply says &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;d love to make Audible work for you&amp;rdquo; and is blank. Since there is no cancel button, I simply ctrl + w&amp;rsquo;d and left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For months I would get an email from Audible saying I got 1 free credit and last month I got an email telling me that if I don&amp;rsquo;t use my credits I would lose them forever.
I had no clue I was paying for these credits, and so what did I do? I spent many of them on books I never listened to after &amp;ldquo;purchasing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the first thing I did was download my statements and disputed the charge in BMO. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that BMO&amp;rsquo;s webapp and mobile app do not work for me on mobile.
To log into BMO, I can only do it on my laptop. After disputing, I then chatted on Amazon support. It took 10 minutes just to find the damn chat because there&amp;rsquo;s audible.ca and audible.com and
my free trial for audible.ca cancelled properly but it was audible.com that didn&amp;rsquo;t go through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After over an hour spent with Amazon support, with me using expletives of course, I left with an anxiety attack and only a refund for one month. All because I was pressured into using the credits last month because apparently if you pay for the right to buy one audio book, you are actually buying the right for only some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subscription model itself is great, but if users are paying for it without using the service or product, then an ethical trillion dollar corporation should do the right thing and cancel the subscription on behalf of the user. Or at least warn the user that their subscription will be cancelled since there is no activity. Furthermore, if a user does want to cancel manually, the first action of cancelling should cancel the subscription and only then should the corporation ask for reasons why. If you want to show users promotions, then make the cancel button an accordion or
a modal. With a modal, you can even implement the logic without javascript, so there&amp;rsquo;s no excuse to make the user press the cancel button 3 times just to finally be free of the subscription.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope BMO will fight these ridiculous and unnecessary charges and if not I will take Amazon to small claims court, because to be honest; I am down $200, I spent an hour with support, my ankle was aching for an hour, and my mouth salivating as if I was about to faint. I am &lt;strong&gt;privileged&lt;/strong&gt; that I can afford to lose thousands of dollars without being homeless, but if this happened to other people there would be sever consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that governments actually start protecting their residents by regulating subscription business models so that users can cancel with a single click and a corporation that fails to abide by these rules should be liable for 40% of their revenue, since a &lt;a href=&#34;https://abc11.com/subscription-not-using-still-paying-didnt-cancel-after-free-trial/12224628/&#34;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; found that 42% of respondents were paying for subscriptions they don&amp;rsquo;t use. Furthermore, corporations should be forced to cancel subscriptions of users who don&amp;rsquo;t user services for two billing cycles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open-Debate Platform</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/open-debate-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 22:58:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/open-debate-platform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to put all the details from my mind into this document, but hopefully
the spirit can be conveyed even if the technical design may be incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy cannot guarantee truth, but can be used to guide discussion &amp;hellip; under a set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-debate-platform&#34; &gt;Open-Debate Platform
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#open-debate-platform&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open-debate platform (ODP) or open-source debate, strongly inspired by open-sourcecode platforms, is about like minded users cooperating informally in order to produce formal arguments in a structured and multiple opinion debate. A debate in this context is simply a question asking for answers. The purpose is to converge and display answers. It&amp;rsquo;s about helping people
finding the truth without bias. If people want to know the best language to learn, they will probably be greeted with &amp;ldquo;English&amp;rdquo;
but if they don&amp;rsquo;t agree that the reasons apply to them, they can look at the next alternative and so on. The platform
allows for efficient analysis of all opinions and arguments. Parts of the implementation follow. I say parts, because there might be race conditions, but the purpose of this document is to communicate the spirit of ODP so that technical solutions can be used and created to preserve and scale this spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Controversy and Extremism&lt;/summary&gt;
Controversy and extremism is expected on a platform like this. The entire point is for an open discussion to
stamp out objectively wrong opinions. For example, murder is wrong; An argument pertaining to killing
would most likely delve into the definition of murder. However, the platform converges upon arguments that are
able to defend their position.
&lt;p&gt;Even though extremism will be present on the platform, uncivil discourse is not to be tolerated.
Civil discussion does not involve calls to genocide or targeting of innocent people. Such a statement would be suppressed,
however arguing whether such things are okay will be permitted. There is a difference between debating something
that is immoral vs. actually acting immorally. Since these arguments don&amp;rsquo;t actually dictate behavior, the ODP
does not have to follow any argument that is able to defend its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ODP can be structured more easily digitally than physically. So the specs are made with that in mind.
Of course, a paper system could replicate this although with unsustainable logistics and so would need to cut some corners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specs&#34; &gt;Specs
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#specs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the spec, some features improve usability and user experience and are not required for the basic
implementation of an ODP. The basic is simply a platform that allows for the interactions described in the previous paragraphs.
One way to accomplish that is given below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;digital-platform&#34; &gt;Digital Platform
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#digital-platform&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most likely a website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website that acts as a host and a gatherer. A gather type system is decentralized but could take lot of technical effort to get right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The digital platform is run by an unbiased &lt;a href=&#34;#operator&#34;&gt;operator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A biased operator invalidates ODP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People can become &lt;a href=&#34;#user&#34;&gt;users&lt;/a&gt; by logging in with email or using public-private key signing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users to able to ask &lt;a href=&#34;#questions&#34;&gt;questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The platform would have an ability to search and explore questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The platform supports a routing protocol like TOR and can be run with JavaScript disabled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;operator&#34; &gt;Operator
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#operator&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An operator is an entity that runs the ODP. Operators are to remove calls to harm. Harm is defined as anything equal to or more than a call to chastise people who haven&amp;rsquo;t acted uncivil in a &lt;strong&gt;formal&lt;/strong&gt; setting. Formality does matter. Unbiased means not using their opinion an a question to censor other opinions. For example, an operator might be pro-Monero, however that does not give them the right to impede and censor civil arguments by pro-bitcoin and pro-ethereum parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;user&#34; &gt;User
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#user&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A user has the ability to interact with the platform and create questions, &lt;a href=&#34;#argument&#34;&gt;arguments&lt;/a&gt;, upvote argument points, and comment in &lt;a href=&#34;#discussions&#34;&gt;discussions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user that creates an argument is also its &lt;a href=&#34;#User::Author&#34;&gt;author&lt;/a&gt; and one of its &lt;a href=&#34;#User::Maintainer&#34;&gt;maintainer&lt;/a&gt;.
A user can become a maintainer but not an author if they accept a maintainer invite from the author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user cannot be an argument maintainer for a topic and also upvote another argument for the same topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;argument&#34; &gt;Argument
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#argument&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For each question, there are responses; also called arguments.
Ultimately, users are responsible for siding with an argument, the platform is just a tool to facilitate open debate as the name conveys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument has at least one reason&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An argument has rebuttals for the arguments next popular and next least popular argument&amp;rsquo;s points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;rebuttal considerations&lt;/summary&gt;
  Replies are to be made to at least 1 rebuttal within 2 weeks or the point/rebuttal will be marked as &#34;failed to defend point/rebuttal&#34;.
  Hence, points/rebuttals can be shown to the user sorted by points/rebuttals defended &amp;rarr; ongoing &amp;rarr; failed to defend.
&lt;p&gt;This time window feature is very important in order to force discourse. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make 1 rebuttal and never respond again. Every response to a rebuttal must address the rebuttal fully. Not addressing a rebuttal fully makes the rebuttal valid. In that way, points and rebuttals can follow a thread type of structure to allow multiple replies and rebuttals per point rather than batching all rebuttals for a point into one. For less popular arguments, operators are allowed to be lenient about the forced rebuttal rule. I&amp;rsquo;d say if there are more than 5 argument, the bottom 50% won&amp;rsquo;t need to comply with the forced discussion. This is because it&amp;rsquo;s more likely these projects are arguing with bad faith characters and so the operator can use their own prioritization method for rule violation reports.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/details&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each question, arguments should be sorted by number of upvotes. Upvotes are not an actual indication of quality, only of popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No more than 10 maintainers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users click an argument, they should be shown the list of points for that argument and rebuttals to those points by the other two projects. Arguments can also rebut other arguments that are more popular or less popular, but it does not force the other argument to reply. Replying to rebuttals is required for arguments that are beside each other in popularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Rogue Behavior Considerations&lt;/summary&gt;
Arguments can be recreated (forked) in case of rogue or dormant maintainers. Since people can change
their minds, even if they decide to mess up the old argument they were supporting, history can be restored by a maintainer
in the same argument or by a proponent through forks.
If done correctly, each point has an associated history and id for each point in history.
Then, the upvotes can be restored as long as the users have no upvoted something new, and that point id does not exist
in any older forks. This way, the damage of griefing is reduced. These are all technical discussions though that uphold the
spirit of ODP.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Bad faith considerations&lt;/summary&gt;
It is up to operators how to deal with arguing in circles; if people are arguing in circles it is best to close the rebuttal. Arguing in circles usually indicates one party is not acting in good faith. Rebuttals can be reported as irrelevant and will shadow ban
the user. Shadow ban in this context means that the user will see the platform as if their action was valid.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;discussions&#34; &gt;Discussions
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#discussions&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussions are informal communication features. They should be included for each argument, and each arguments merge requests.
Responses in discussions are called comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argument discussions can be moderated &lt;strong&gt;with bias&lt;/strong&gt; by the arguments &lt;a href=&#34;#User::Maintainer&#34;&gt;maintainers&lt;/a&gt; themselves since their role is to improve
discussion pertaining to their argument, not the question being answered. Comments are informal, so they can only be from proponents
of said argument. This should reduce the number of bad actors as proponents have to upvote the argument itself. The maintainers
are there to clean up remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;userauthor&#34; &gt;User::Author
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#userauthor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A user that started the argument. They have the power to delete the argument if there
are less than 3 proponents of the argument. All authors are considered a maintainer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usermaintainer&#34; &gt;User::Maintainer
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#usermaintainer&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A maintainer is a user who has the ability to edit. Authors are considered maintainers but
not vice versa. To make a user a maintainer of an argument requires 75% of maintainers to vote.
There can only be up to 10 maintainers including the author.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arguments should have a change history so even if a &lt;a href=&#34;#User::Maintainer&#34;&gt;maintainer&lt;/a&gt; goes rogue, damage should be easily reversible.
If all maintainers go rogue, the author can request operator intervention to kick out the rogue maintainers. Or if the author goes rogue, the maintainers can request an operator intervention. This is where operator neutrality becomes important although not required since arguments can be &amp;ldquo;forked&amp;rdquo;, and the rogue argument basically left to die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;question&#34; &gt;Question
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#question&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A question can also be referred to as a topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can ask subjective questions about topics, but questions that spark debate should be prioritized. Think &amp;ldquo;what is &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; good ice cream flavor&amp;rdquo; vs. &amp;ldquo;what is the &lt;strong&gt;best&lt;/strong&gt; ice cream flavor&amp;rdquo;. There is a difference, the former seeks to get a good sample, but the latter seeks to find the best answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A question is a duplicate if it conveys the same message or is equal ignoring case and non-grammatic symbols. If it is the latter,
the question can be disallowed from creation, but the former should be marked as duplicate. Duplicate questions should be searchable but not prioritized. A question marked as a duplicate should allow the question creator to argue that the question was incorrectly marked as a duplicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details&gt;
&lt;summary&gt;Censorship considerations&lt;/summary&gt;
Many times on Stackoverflow, questions are marked as duplicate incorrectly on Stackoverflow where as actual duplicates fly by the radar.
These questions are not technical at all, only discussion prompts, so it is imperative to not censor valid questions.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;merge-request&#34; &gt;Merge Request
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#merge-request&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A merge request is a request by a user to add a point or rebuttal to an argument. Merge requests can only be
merged be maintainers and should support informal discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reason-or-point&#34; &gt;Reason or Point
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#reason-or-point&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A single reason that supports the arguments thesis. A point can have upvotes but every
edit or deletion resets the upvote to 0 and thus removes proponents of the argument.
An argument&amp;rsquo;s star count is equal to the sum of upvotes of its reasons which is also the number of proponents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usercontributor&#34; &gt;User::Contributor
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#usercontributor&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A user is considered a contributor if one of their changes in in the argument even if has been overwritten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;userproponent&#34; &gt;User::Proponent
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#userproponent&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A user is considered a proponent of an argument if they&amp;rsquo;ve upvoted a reason of the argument or are a maintainer for an argument.
Only reasoning points of the argument can be upvoted and a user is no longer a proponent if the point they upvoted
gets modified or deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-logistics&#34; &gt;Platform Logistics
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#platform-logistics&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A platform would be created by an operator. The operator has to make a legally bound contract
with all participants that stipulates that the operator will not manipulate or censor civil arguments and should also provide
visitors and a link to download the platform source code (any license allowed). This holds the operator accountable for abuse.
Abuse would either be easily detectable or non-harmful to the goal of figuring out the best arguments. Platforms
can compete with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an operator deleted a comment, an argument, an arguments points, it is pretty noticeable and easy to prove using archive websites.
Vote inflating is possible, but that is why the operator needs to show the UI in terms of rebuttals. Operators that can be shown
to not follow the specs mentioned in this article won&amp;rsquo;t be considered an open-debate platform. If required, I can test out
a platform and classify or declassify it as an open-debate platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;remarks&#34; &gt;Remarks
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#remarks&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to implement this, but I&amp;rsquo;m leaving this here for someone to pursue. My goal with this is to improve unity and reduce polarizations. We need to stop with the harassment of people that hold an opinion. An opinion is much different from
an action and we need to make that distinction by showing our tolerance for opposing opinions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people who think it&amp;rsquo;s okay for the tolerant to be intolerant of the intolerant but that&amp;rsquo;s contradictory. The best way
to debate against someone who promotes intolerance is to tell them that they are only able to promote intolerance because of the tolerant society. If society operated as it did in the past where tolerance is just the intolerance of the majority, then have have learned nothing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
