<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>canada on ELL Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/canada/</link>
    <description>ELL Blog (canada)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 01:18:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Canada</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 01:18:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article will be the one stop shop for my thoughts on Canada.
Please refer to the table of contents to read sections that are interesting to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#housing-affordability&#34;&gt;Housing Affordability&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#reducing-demand---major-speculation-tax&#34;&gt;Reducing Demand - Major Speculation Tax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#increasing-supply---vacant-homes&#34;&gt;Increasing Supply - Vacant Homes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#increasing-supply---prioritized-development&#34;&gt;Increasing Supply - Prioritized Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-ideal-canadian-life&#34;&gt;The Ideal Canadian Life&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#living-situation&#34;&gt;Living Situation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#income&#34;&gt;Income&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#125000-careers&#34;&gt;$125,000 Careers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-government&#34;&gt;The Government&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#a-fair-electoral-system&#34;&gt;A Fair Electoral System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#taxes&#34;&gt;Taxes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#organ-donors&#34;&gt;Organ Donors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#national-defence&#34;&gt;National Defence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;housing-affordability&#34; &gt;Housing Affordability
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#housing-affordability&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let us start off with one of the biggest issues facing Canadians under the age of 40.
The best way to deal with housing affordability is to make homes affordable for those that don&amp;rsquo;t own a home. This means reducing the demand from non-primrary home buyers and increasing housing supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Domestic speculation is a probelm in Canada. Temporarily banning foreign buyers or taxing vacancy is not going to bring affordability. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t go far enough. You have to ban foreign ownership itself.
Why do we even let foreign buyers purchase residential homes in the first place? That itself should be taxable. Call it a foreign ownership tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Canadian citizen, I would expect to not be able to purchase a US home, unless I have a green card or was a dual citizen, even if I have work permit. That is not the case, but that&amp;rsquo;s because the US econmy is 10x Canada&amp;rsquo;s. Likewise, foreigners who &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt; reside in Canada, should not be able to buy properties in Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not think housing should be something where land lords can live off the rent they make. That is absurd, and thus companies should not be allowed to buy residential properties either. If companies own residential properties, it should be because of reasons like developing the property itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for undeveloped land, we could say that development of the land has to be started within a year of purchase, otherwise both the previous and the current owner get fined. However, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is a problem yet with undeveloped land, so let&amp;rsquo;s keep this up our sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reducing-demand---major-speculation-tax&#34; &gt;Reducing Demand - Major Speculation Tax
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#reducing-demand---major-speculation-tax&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To reduce demand, we will add a buyers (speculation) tax on non-primary home purchases for homes transactions that are more than $150,000. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to own more homes than people in your immediate family. For clarification on the definition of an immediate family, a couple with one kid over 18 can buy 3 homes but a couple with a kid less than 18 can only buy 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose this speculation tax to start at 50% and to modify it the next year. If it&amp;rsquo;s too low, we&amp;rsquo;ll make it 100%. If prices dramatically fall, we will get hated by property owners but at least the U40 population will vote for us again. If even a 100% tax is too low, we can further reduce the 150k threshold so that most couples would have to use their secndary home allowance itself as the other tax-free property. For example a secondary property could be a storage area, a cottage, or a simple office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing home owners with more homes than people in their immediate family have 6 months to pay the buyers tax on their (# homes - # family members) most expensive homes. So even if a couples primary residence is the most expensive, they have to pay the buyers tax on it and not their cheaper investment properties. The problem in Canada isn&amp;rsquo;t just foreign spending, it&amp;rsquo;s domestic speculation. We need to tackle our own greed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this buyers tax, one could argue that a couple itself is treated as one in the eyes of the law, and therefore they should be given one less home to own, but I think that would mess with something other than housing prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m up for debate on whether to include properties that were inherited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This buyers tax should be implemented federally. People who are buying homes in multiple provinces are definitely upper middle class or rich. Therefore, a 50% or even 100% tax is not a problem if they are buying to live rather than to rent. Imagine a multi millionaire; that 500k property now costs 1M, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increasing-supply---vacant-homes&#34; &gt;Increasing Supply - Vacant Homes
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#increasing-supply---vacant-homes&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was watching a video on a $20M abandoned mansion in Toronto. I searched more up. There are many vacant or abandend properties in Toronto.
This neeeds to stop. The governments on all levels need to enact a law that would force current property owners and banks to either find a tenant
within 6 months, or be forced to auction the property off through a government website with no reservation price. This would end up housing
60,000 groups of people in Toronto alone and probably. A vacanacy tax is only an incentive to sell, but does not actually
solve housing. Nationally, we can conservatively estimate there to be $100,000. The purchasing agreement would be
1 month to change the primary residences, find a tenant, or to create renovation plan with details.
With thed demand constrained, it&amp;rsquo;ll mostly be a primary residence thing rather than finding tenant.
To prevent renovation abuse, we should enact a fine on the renovation filer 2 years later.
This also prevents owners from abusing the renovation clause in order to flip the house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increasing-supply---prioritized-development&#34; &gt;Increasing Supply - Prioritized Development
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#increasing-supply---prioritized-development&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the case reducing demand isn&amp;rsquo;t enough, the affordability problem is clearly supply sided. My proposal is that we use the tax revenue from the speculation tax to fund housing developments. The government should not spend this money. We should issue loans at an interest rate equal to the rate banks offer. We can either create a new department would handle this stuff or if there is a lot of money, loan the money to credit unions directly and let them issue the loans for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The procedure for giving out loans is as follows. Start with neglected and cheaper provinces. The residents of these provinces have the least purchasing power and therefore are more vulnerable to housing affordability. New Brunswick for one. The territories have their own problem like Nunavut needing $100M for their water plant but I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to look at their budget to figure out if they just want a handout or are being serious. We want to fund housing developments in three provinces concurrently. These provinces are picked by a median income ascending. Again, territories are something else, so we need a different strategy for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long term, we should focus on more than fixing housing prices, but distributing them equally across Canada which includes distributing job opportunity and incomes a cross the board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ideal-canadian-life&#34; &gt;The Ideal Canadian Life
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-ideal-canadian-life&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we can move on to idealism rather than current issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the ideal Canadian life? I want to answer this question. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to fall prey to the unlimited wants nature, so we&amp;rsquo;ll have to answer what would make a Canadian content without bias?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The age at which this idealism should be achieved for Canadians is 30 years old.
I believe by 30 people would start a family. I also know that by 30,
we start to visually age. So at 30, we want to be living our ideal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;living-situation&#34; &gt;Living Situation
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#living-situation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t made up my mind on whether to have children or not, but in the off chance that I
do, I&amp;rsquo;d probably have 2 children. Therefore, an ideal &lt;em&gt;house&lt;/em&gt; will have 3-4 bedrooms.
The extra one is for guests. I think there should also be 3 washrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One should plan out the general location where they want to build a family right after marriage&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; because then you won&amp;rsquo;t be locked into a location because of work, family, or friends. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure this is one of the biggest factors preventing people from moving to affordable locations. The other factors are activities which we&amp;rsquo;ll get to now. Personally, I would love to live in New Brunswick, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to cater to all. If you want nightlife, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to lower your bedroom and washroom numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activities&#34; &gt;Activities
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#activities&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to think from other peoples&amp;rsquo; shoes. We have two ways to go for this. We can go suburban or urban.
For sake of the American Dream &lt;em&gt;fantasy&lt;/em&gt;, we&amp;rsquo;ll go the suburban route. So our activities consist of: waterpark within two hours, theme park within 2 hours, a picnic type park within 15 minutes, biking routes, tennis court, basketball court, soccer fields. Also a gym if you want to improve your physique. You can reduce or increase this list based on your wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;income&#34; &gt;Income
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#income&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Warning, this section is completely scuffed; as in I might&amp;rsquo;ve made more than one blunder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thought process for this is simple. We need to calculate ideal income based on how much we need to invest in the stock market, how much we will pay for mortgage, and how much we would want to spend per month on other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ia big one, if not the biggest. Typically, we want $1M in cash by the time of retirement. Why? With $1M and 7% average annual S&amp;amp;P 500 return, we get $50,000-$70,000 per year if income tax is payable or not. I believe this is enough since we assume there is no mortgage and we aren&amp;rsquo;t going on spending sprees. With disposable income of $4,000 / month which would be worth $2,000 minimum accounting for inflation, we&amp;rsquo;re good.
In total, household networth at retirement (age 55) should be $1.5M to $3M. In business classes, we&amp;rsquo;d do some math to calculate the money needed at retirement in order to die with X amount of money. However, since we are dealing with an ideal lifestyle, we want to be able to live off passive income and leave our children with something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to employ some financial equations now to account for real stock market growth of 8.66%.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; To get this number, I used 35 years of data from Jan 1st 1986 to Dec 31 2021, adjust for inflation, add dividends, and subtract 0.03% because VOO is the cheapest S&amp;amp;P 500 exchange traded fund (ETF).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to update my old investing article, but I summarized the basics &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/investing&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can use this Python function I made in 2019/2020 to first calculate how much we need to put into the stock market per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#d0d0d0;background-color:#202020;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-py&#34; data-lang=&#34;py&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#6ab825;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#447fcf&#34;&gt;get_savings_amt&lt;/span&gt;(future_savings, years_to_retirement, interest_rate,
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;                    compounds_per_year=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;, startwith=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, saving_period=&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt;):
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ed9d13&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ed9d13&#34;&gt;    Calculates how much you need to save per month to retire given the parameters
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ed9d13&#34;&gt;    &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    r, m, n = interest_rate, compounds_per_year, years_to_retirement * saving_period
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    efr = (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; + r/m) ** (m / saving_period) - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    already_secured = startwith * (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; + r / m) ** (m * years_to_retirement)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    future_savings -= already_secured
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#6ab825;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; future_savings * efr / ((&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; + efr) ** n - &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#999;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;# assume we start working at 25, we start with $0, and we compound yearly&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#999;font-style:italic&#34;&gt;# multiply by two to account for market volatility&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; get_savings_amt(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1000000&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;30&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;0.0866&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;52&lt;/span&gt;) * &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#3677a9&#34;&gt;288.51322722512805&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the future I will try testing this out on actual data and seeing if the results are as intended. The market is volatile so we can&amp;rsquo;t use an answer based on a monotonic assumption without double checking. In order to account for volatility, I doubled my answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$288/week translates to $1,248/month or $14,976/yr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A down payment on a $2M home is $400,000 and if we want to buy it when we are 30, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to save (household) $80,000
per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;What&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Yearly Amount (CAD)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Investing&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Downpayment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Food&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15 * 30 = 10,950&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Two Cars&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15,000 to 30,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mortgage/Rent&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,600 to 9,305.68&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Monthlies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250 * 12 = 3,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Misc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10,000 to 12,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vacation???&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Upper TOTAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;163,255&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Upper Income&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lower TOTAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146,255&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lower Income&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Per Person&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;125,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of rounding and over-estimations, but overall I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my results. The upper bound is assuming you are
a baller and want a $2M home. That&amp;rsquo;s not me, but some people out there want to be entitled to that. Personally, $1M home is enough for me, especially if it&amp;rsquo;s in New Brunswick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is the problem then huh? When half of Canadians earn less than 80,000, the ideal Canadian life is unattainable unless you&amp;rsquo;re in specific career paths. So we&amp;rsquo;ll look at careers that can earn 125,000 including alternative careers, as well as what Canada (government) can do to improve the situation (increasing purchasing power).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;125000-careers&#34; &gt;$125,000 Careers
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#125000-careers&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software engineering of course. Product managers and project managers also make this, but those career paths are really talked about. Someone should make an article on those two career paths. What else? Lawyers, doctors, investment banking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like writing this section, so I&amp;rsquo;ll stop for now. I think the issue is that there&amp;rsquo;s no way to make a 30 year old experienced enough to earn that much in some of these career paths that start off only at $80,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-government&#34; &gt;The Government
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-government&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Engineers are grossly underpaid in Canada and the US. Not all engineering challenges are complete, yet these people get paid pebbles. I propose some industries that are lacking in Canada. We need Canadian companies for these engineering innovation industries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CPU chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;electronics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;automobile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aerospace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agriculture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;telecommunications outside of Ontario and Quebec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lumber vertical integration (companies that use wood extensively)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also abolish the P. Eng fee. What a useless fee. People should not be sitting on their asses while others work hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-fair-electoral-system&#34; &gt;A Fair Electoral System
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-fair-electoral-system&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the 2021 Federal election, I was dismayed at how horribly parliament seats reflected who voters voted. So I came up
with a proof-of-concept of a new electroal system that combines local representation with a proportional voting. I&amp;rsquo;m calling it the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/representative-proportional-voting&#34;&gt;Represenative Proportional Voting&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s in its infancy at the moment,
but I hope to formalize the algorithm and system in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;taxes&#34; &gt;Taxes
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#taxes&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;TODO: split into different types of taxes (income, property, sales, sin, capital gains, tax ethics, duties/tariffs, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government goal should be to use taxes to create a sustainable environment for innovation and wealth. Taxes should be used wisely with the end goal of lowering taxes. Governments should create self-sustainable nationlised businesses where the nature is a priviledge rather than a need. Things like health care should remain nationalized, but private health care should also be allowed as it is in Quebec. Not sure why courts in Canada think that private health care access takes away from Canadians who are using the public health care system, but hey I&amp;rsquo;m not a judge and they aren&amp;rsquo;t economists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sales-tax&#34; &gt;Sales Tax
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#sales-tax&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Should not exist. There are so many exceptions and the CRA does not do a good job at exempting everything. For example, the CRA reqeuires you to have a phone number
in order to login because of 2FA, but phone plans and phones have salex tax. These are necessities and a sales tax is regressive&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in this case.
There are simply too many cases of figuring out what is a necessity and what isn&amp;rsquo;t. Not to mention that on top of federal sales tax, each province has its
own sales tax rules. Therefore a national business needs to report to so many different provinces or join something like US&amp;rsquo;s nexus. So then implementing a
sales tax fattens the government (additional beauracracy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tariffs&#34; &gt;Tariffs
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tariffs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There should be almost 0 tariffs and import duties. If people want to shop in America, good for them. A trip to America is not free, so why make citizens&amp;rsquo; lives more expensive?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organ-donors&#34; &gt;Organ Donors
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#organ-donors&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;People can choose to donate their organs for free upon death, but yet organs go for
thousands of dollars in black markets? Governments should incentivize people in poverty to become organ donors so that when they die, their family will receive a payment instead of being left with nothing. A charity should be started for this at the very least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34; &gt;Education
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#education&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a country to be competitive on the global stage, education must be done in a way that strives for perfection and without excuses.
It is one of the things that I&amp;rsquo;m okay with requiring mandating. People under 18 are simply not mature or intelligent enough to make their own decisions
in life, and the current state does not integrate elementary well with high school well with post-secondary. In high school, there is school
every day, for four courses, in a longer term than university, where there are 5 courses, not every day, with a shorter term, harder, expensive,
and a higher risk of failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is &amp;ldquo;so good.&amp;rdquo; Good question, I will leave this as an exercise for the reader. Just kidding; This is a TODO since like I said in the introduction,
this article is a collection of my thoughts on Canada that come to mind. I also try to keep it as articulate and cohesive as possible,
rather than vomit words. I aswell try to add my quirks and humor where I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;national-defence&#34; &gt;National Defence
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#national-defence&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the key functions of the government is to support national defence. Now even though Canada is part of NATO, NATO members are supposed to spend
2% of their GDP on national defence. I disagree with this percentage idea. If a percentage, it should be based on tax revenue, not GDP. Better yet,
there should be a plan on how to spend on national defence. There are 4+ things when it comes to national defence. Air, Water, Land, range weapons (i.e. missiles/nukes),
and air-defence (e.g. Iron Dome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;airforce&#34; &gt;Airforce
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#airforce&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;An airforce is crucical. A single aircraft can devastate many land units, so an air-defence system is just as crucial. An airforce should be as mobile
as possible and should be not be crippled with one attack. In other words, there should be multiple air-bases and the location of these bases need to completely
classified or opaqued, but the existence of them should be stated. This is an equal balance between government secrets in the name of national defence. Some
governments, like the USA, take it too far and classify even operations. An operation should be classified until it&amp;rsquo;s over. Then it should be made as transparent as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;navy&#34; &gt;Navy
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#navy&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Navy is useful for shipping as well as long-lasting operations. It&amp;rsquo;s also useful to for saving the fuel of aircrafts and keeping a moving aircraft base.
That is, instead of having fixed aircraft bases, we can have mobile bases. Hypothetically, aircraft carriers reduce the need of fixed airbases and thus
we could save money while improving the reliability of the air-force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;army&#34; &gt;Army
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#army&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The army is useful when aircrafts and missiles cannot be used luxuriously. An army&amp;rsquo;s strength is determined by both strategy and manpower. This is because, one
person could either take out 100+ enemy soldiers, or die without being of any use. For countries like Canada, we should reduce the school length term for
grade 12ers so that their 4 month summer can be spent learning how to be part of the military. I am against military conscription, but with a trained
civilian population, we will be able to depend more on the power of patriotism, civil duty, and volunteerism. A person with even basic military education will
be more willing than a 30 year old who has never shot a gun before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This training will not be as strict as the army and military is at the moment. I am strongly against force, so things like being forced to get a haircut, cost-savings
on living quarters, and drill sargents are a big no. People should not be scared of the training, but rather take it calmly. The entire course should
be able to be completed in 3 months, there should be lots of free time mixed in so that people don&amp;rsquo;t lose their minds. Since the program can be completed in 3
months, an extra 2 weeks of bonus or specialized education should be added for people who completed the education on time while the people who lagged behind,
can catch up on their basics. This is perfect because a) does not stop the progress of fast learners b) gives slower people more time to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By marriage I mean the unification of partners in a relationship rather than the legal sense&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moneychimp.com/features/market_cagr.htm&#34;&gt;Moneychimp - CAGR Stock Market Last 35 Years.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sales tax is regressive because people with lower income pay a higher percentage of their income as sales tax if they bought the same goods.
Paying for groceries is a lot harder on poorer people.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing (Equities)</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 01:18:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/investing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My updated investing article. I wrote this with an emphasis on safety rather than making money.
I&amp;rsquo;ll start off with the tips and then go over what you need to know to follow these tips/rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#broker&#34;&gt;Broker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#accounts&#34;&gt;Accounts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#norberts-gambit&#34;&gt;Norbert&amp;rsquo;s Gambit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#exchange-traded-funds-etfs&#34;&gt;Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#orders&#34;&gt;Orders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#options-and-futures&#34;&gt;Options and Futures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#crypto-currency&#34;&gt;Crypto-Currency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34; &gt;Tips
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tips&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re either investing for the compound effect, in which case you need to invest often, or to live off the yield, in which case you can invest once and sell shares monthly for income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want the benefits of compounding, invest on a weeky basis (pick a random day of th week to do it on)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During bull markets, invest in $VOO; the Beta coefficient plays a huge role during the inevitable bear markets and you should try to avoid that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever the NASDAQ-100 is down -15% or more from its peak, invest in the $QQQ rather than the $VOO. The $QQQ will give a heuristically inflation adjusted CAGR of 10% (dividends excluded). The extra 2% is a big deal when we talk about decades. I&amp;rsquo;m actually not too sure about this recommendation, so stick to the $VOO for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not try to time the market. The weekly schedule solves the issues of impatience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not pick stocks unless you are less than 25 years old. When you are less than 25, you can afford to lose all yur money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34; &gt;Getting Started
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#getting-started&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;About what I said earlier 😅. I&amp;rsquo;m simply not in the mood to improve on my first investing article I created in 2020.
I can tell you what to learn though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;broker&#34; &gt;Broker
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#broker&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You need a broker. If you are in Canada and are planning on investing weekly, go with RBC Direct Investing.
If you are in America, pick &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinhood.com/&#34;&gt;Robinhood&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend Questrade or Wealthsimple because the experience for investing in US stocks is abysmal and I&amp;rsquo;d rather pay $10 to avoid waiting in a customer support chat and paying Wealthsimple&amp;rsquo;s FX fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;accounts&#34; &gt;Accounts
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#accounts&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFSA: Tax Free Savings Account. Maximize this before your RRSP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(R)RSP: Registered Retirement Savings Plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RESP: Registered Education Savings Plan (CAD only, so invest wisely!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cash: Use this after maxxing your registered accounts. Tax implications exist when you make capital gains, so avoid selling unless you know what you are doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Margin: do not get it. It&amp;rsquo;s best to not open one since using the Margin is tempting if you know more than the basics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;norberts-gambit&#34; &gt;Norbert&amp;rsquo;s Gambit
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#norberts-gambit&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are in Canada and want to invest in American stocks (or vice versa), you need to learn Norbert&amp;rsquo;s Gambit to avoid the percentage foreign exchange fees. This is incredbly simple for RBC. Buy DLR and short DLR.U. RBC will take care of the settling automatically so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to spend more time or money unlike Questrade and Wealthsimple. Questrade and Wealthsimple&amp;rsquo;s experience and FX fees is &lt;em&gt;bakwas&lt;/em&gt; (outrageous). A new broker needs to be started in Canada or someone new needs to lead RBC Direct Investing. Hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll be me, but I have things to do too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exchange-traded-funds-etfs&#34; &gt;Exchange-Traded Funds (ETFs)
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#exchange-traded-funds-etfs&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many ETFs and they consist of a basket of securities. Financial securities are picked and maintained by the creator of the ETF. For example, the $VOO S&amp;amp;P 500 Index ETF is run by Vanguard. Each ETF usually has an expense ratio. That means you get charged for owning the ETF. I recommend $VOO instead of $SPY because the expense ratio for $VOO is  0.03% compared to $SPY&amp;rsquo;s 0.09%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;orders&#34; &gt;Orders
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#orders&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit order: a bid to buy a stock at a max price OR an ask to sell your stock at min price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market order: buying whatever the sellers are offering. Use with discrestion and for high volume stocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To buy a stock, place a buy limit order below market price and if it isn&amp;rsquo;t filled by 3-4 PM EST, keep increasing the bid to the asking price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sell a stock, place a sell limit order above market price and if it isn&amp;rsquo;t filed by 3-4 PM EST, keep lowering the ask to the bid price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;options-and-futures&#34; &gt;Options and Futures
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#options-and-futures&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless you are less than 25 years old or a gambler, do not even bother with options or futures. It&amp;rsquo;s best to stay away. This is for people who can afford to lose money or know what they are doing (i.e. you work in Equities).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-currency&#34; &gt;Crypto-Currency
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#crypto-currency&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sike! There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as &amp;ldquo;investing&amp;rdquo; in crypto-currency. You are either gambling or want to experience P2P money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Buy Monero in Canada</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/how-to-buy-monero-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 22:56:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/how-to-buy-monero-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be testing all of these methods except LocalMonero since the actual fee there is at least 20% as of 2022/4/21.
Testing is done by using converting the received XMR to CAD using the currency pair rates at the start of each new pair transaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-float&#34; &gt;Fixed Float
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#fixed-float&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you can purchase XLM via &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.newton.co/r/YREHXA&#34;&gt;Newton&lt;/a&gt;, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://fixedfloat.com/XLM/XMR?ref=dybjhjrb&#34;&gt;Fixed Float&lt;/a&gt; for 0.5% - 1% fee per trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kraken&#34; &gt;Kraken
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#kraken&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cad---usd---xmr&#34; &gt;CAD -&amp;gt; USD -&amp;gt; XMR
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#cad---usd---xmr&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A deposit fee of 0.1% for etransfer (3k limit), a USD conversion fee of 0.2%, and a 0.16% post limit order fee to buy XMR, and a flat network fee to withdraw.
In total, that&amp;rsquo;s 0.46% as a maker and a 0.56% fee as a taker. You can use Etana to forgo the deposit fee, but I&amp;rsquo;m unsure if Etana has its
own fees and it does require KYC. A wire transfer requires being in-persona which might have its own fees; it does for my business account!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My own results for the etransfer deposit method are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CAD/USD = 1.25625&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XMR/USD = 285.48&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a etransfer of 3,000 CAD becomes 2,970 CAD converted to 2,359.45 USD bought 8.2648521800 XMR withdrew and received 8.25152 XMR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fee = 3,000 - 8.25152 * 285.48 * 1.25625 = 40.72&amp;hellip; = 1.3574%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to set the limit order one cent less than market with &lt;strong&gt;post&lt;/strong&gt; selected unless you are treating it as a security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The etransfer deposit fee took the largest chunk! I&amp;rsquo;ll have to test the other methods to compare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlm---usd---xmr&#34; &gt;XLM -&amp;gt; USD -&amp;gt; XMR
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#xlm---usd---xmr&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depositing XLM only incurs network fees. Selling to USD has a 0.16% fee for a post limit order, and a post limit order on XMR is another 0.16%.
That&amp;rsquo;s 0.34% as a 2x maker and 0.52% as a 2x taker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usd---xmr&#34; &gt;USD -&amp;gt; XMR
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#usd---xmr&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need a USD bank account for this and you&amp;rsquo;ll need Etana which is another KYC hurdle. Theoretically this method results in
a 0.16% fee as a maker and a 0.26% fee as a taker. I say theoretically though since I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there&amp;rsquo;s any fee from Etana&amp;rsquo;s side and
it&amp;rsquo;s not practical as like I said before, you need to have USD beforehand without a conversion fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-monero&#34; &gt;Local Monero
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#local-monero&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://localmonero.co/?rc=nde2&#34;&gt;Local Monero&lt;/a&gt; is less private than FixedFloat and more than exchanges but costs way more (20%+ via CAD, 4.4%+ via XLM),
requires greater level of trust, and takes a longer time than exchanges ignoring the inital KYC time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nehdddktmhvqklsnkjqcbpmb63htee2iznpcbs5tgzctipxykpj6yrid.onion/?rc=nde2&#34;&gt;Local Monero TOR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lm.i2p/?rc=nde2&#34;&gt;Local Monero I2P&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34; &gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, it&amp;rsquo;s better to buy XLM on Newton, sell it for USD on Kraken, and then buy XMR with the USD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fill out W-8 BEN Form in Canada</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/filling-out-w-8ben-form-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:37:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/filling-out-w-8ben-form-canada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/fw8ben.pdf&#34;&gt;Download the form.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blank-lines&#34; &gt;Blank Lines
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#blank-lines&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;lines 5, 6b, 7, 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1&#34; &gt;Part 1
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-1&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 1: First and Last name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 2: Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 3: Address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 4: Address if differs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 6a: SIN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2&#34; &gt;Part 2
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-2&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line 9: Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3&#34; &gt;Part 3
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#part-3&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the box&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Representative Proportional Voting</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/representative-proportional-voting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 11:58:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/representative-proportional-voting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The one argument against common proportional voting systems is &amp;ldquo;local represenation matters.&amp;rdquo;
Party-list proportional representation is the formal term for it but it does not care about local representations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this we still keep the same voting methods. The only change is which MP actually get elected. Once all the votes are counted, first determine independent MPs using first past the post. Remove these seats from the total seats. Then use Huntington–Hill method to determine number of seats for each party (independents are not one party). Primary allocation is done using any party with more than hare quota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To protect independents we give independents priority when picking MP&amp;rsquo;s for each riding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seats are allocated,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From smallest seats party to largest:
Find riding from unelected riding&amp;rsquo;s with the highest percentage voting for that party (use sorting algorithm). Elect the party MP for that riding. Remove riding from unelected riding&amp;rsquo;s. Repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
