<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wisdom on ELL Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/wisdom/</link>
    <description>ELL Blog (Wisdom)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 17:35:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Greed?</title>
      <link>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/what-is-greed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 17:35:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.elijahlopez.ca/posts/what-is-greed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Greed is wanting so much that fulfilling your want would actually take away from someone else and thus have a negative impact on other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to attain as much money (profit) as possible so instead of cutting useless jobs, pay the useful jobs as low of a wage as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to acquire the most land in order to make more money leasing it, or acquiring as many properties as possible in order to make more money from renting it in addition to paying for the property&amp;rsquo;s equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to have multiple concurrent partners which not only forces your partners to be tolerant of each other but also removes them from the dating pool for people with self-respect who are seeking monogamous relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to eat the tastiest food which only harms yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to want the best looks which leads to envy and dragging other people down. &amp;lsquo;Haters be hating&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed to attain power person in the room so you snub others, talk condescendingly, and act pretentiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed for power so you create bureaucracy which takes away freedom of others and requires your explicit approval. This is seen in corporate bylaws, board of directors, and corporate policies, and not to forget all governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed for stimulation and a dopamine release so you end up losing self-control and harming others or you end up participating in activities which end up being harmful with repeated and long-term partaking; addiction and a destruction of your dopamine receptors. An addiction to drugs makes you unfit to work, is a money sink, and can end up with you being homeless. An addiction to porn can lead you to have ED, get desensitized to women, and so you experience less pleasure than otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greed for a better life; Combined with an ethical standard, rather than enslave and treat humans poorly, innovation/productivity/efficiency can be attained. Without a moral or ethical standard, time saved might not be a
good enough incentive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time should be the ultimate incentive. If it saves time, it is worth pursuing. Patents are only useful when the goods &amp;amp; services cannot be provided by the people who require the product and does not need to be regulated to the specific details; pharmaceutical drugs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
